Ian Wijma

E: ian@wij.ma

P: 0414951337

W: ian.wij.ma

A: 14 Bootle Place, Phillip, ACT

Summary

Hey there, I'm Ian Wijma and moved from The Netherlands to Australia in August 2019. I have 5+ years experience in developing solutions and products. Where I have worked on front-end, back-end, integrations and deployed solutions.

I have professional experience with techniques like JavaScript, NodeJS, PHP, PostgreSQL, MySQL, React, React Native and WordPress.

I also love to play around with different techniques in my spare time like TypeScript, Electron, GO, Rust, Java, MongoDB, vueJS and many others.

I'm also a big advocate of Linux and have professional and personal experience with the system. Personally I run on Debian based OS's but I have experience with other flavours as well.

Career History

Senior Software Developer at StoreKeeper Company B.V. Sep 2017 - Present (3 years and 2 month)

StoreKeeper is a company based in Enschede, The Netherlands that provides an eCommerce solution for shops with an online and offline shop. Where I helped build their product from day 1. My tasks and responsibilities where there as followed:

- I worked on the full product stack, back-end and front-end.
- I worked tightly with the design team to come up with a design for a new feature or change.
- I worked with all kinds of groups to create internal tools to improve the customer experience.
- I worked with other developers to develop and maintain a feature to fix a bug.
- I worked on a SAAS product that consists of multiple pieces of software to provide the ultimate eCommerce solution for (web)shops.

Software Developer at Upx Systems B.V.

Aug 2015 - Sept 2017 (2 years and 1 month)

UPX is a company that taught me programming on a professional level. They worked on custom solutions for their customers. My tasks and responsibilities where there as followed:

- Here I worked as a front-end and app developer with backend developers.
- I worked with a team of 2 5 people on one project from first contact to delivery.
- I was in meetings with the customers, as a communication layer between Development and the customer.
- I worked on various solutions from CRM to internal social platforms to eCommerce.
- I helped the company migrate from UPX B.V. to StoreKeeper B.V.

Trainee at Nubium

Jan 2015 - Jun 2015 (5 months)

Nubium is a company that does online marketing and web development. My tasks and responsibilities where there as followed:

- My main task here was to make some of their customers' websites work on mobile.
- I also worked on creating new sites.
- I worked in a professional software development

environment

Warehouse Storeperson at Albert Heijn

Jul 2010 - Aug 2013 (3 years and 1 month)

Albert Heijn is one of The Netherlands biggest Grocery stores. I started out as a clerk, but quickly found interest in maintaining the warehouse. This was my first real job. My tasks and responsibilities where there as followed:

- Unloading and loading trucks.
- Preparing the warehouse for the evening shifts
- Stocking the vegetable and fruit section
- Cleaning up the warehouse at the end of the day.
- Working in a team to finish your task.

Skills

software development, Public Speaking, SQL, NodeJS, CSS, HTML, Hardware, Linux, Mercurial, VueJS, React, PHP, JavaScript, Teamwork, Git, Dutch, English, Debian, React Native, Next.js, TypeScript

Education

Game development at Saxion University

Started 2015

Because I'm highly interested in Games I decided to try out game development at the Saxion University, where after passing the intro exam . During the summer I got more interested in working for a company and learning my craft this way. So I did.

Diploma of Software Development from ROC van Twente Graduated 2012-2015

Although I already knew some programming from personal projects, I decided to follow the software development path of education. Which I graduated with ease.

Diploma of IT support from ROC van Twente Graduated 2010-2012

Here I learned to communicate with non-technical people and work with hardware (Desktops, Laptops and servers).

Languages

English

I speak and write English on a professional level.

Dutch

Dutch is my native tongue.

Twents (dialect)

Twents is my native dialect, which is a dialect of Dutch.

Australian

Because I live in Australia I'm learning as much Australian as I can.